# JOHN AUSTIN MOORE

STAFF SOFTWARF ENGINFER

#### DETAILS

#### **ADDRESS**

8633 Howard Dr Terrell, NC 28682

#### PHONE

(704) 315-7513

#### **EMAIL**

amoore1337@gmail.com

#### **GITHUB**

https://github.com/amoore1337

#### **EDUCATION**

**BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE** 2014

SAMFORD UNIVERSITY, BIRMINGHAM, AL

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

#### **LANGUAGES AND PLATFORMS**

JavaScript / Typescript

HTML / CSS

React

Go

Ruby on Rails

Vue

AnuglarJS / Angular

Node / Express

Python

GraphQL

SQL / NoSQL

Redis

Docker

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Oracle Certified Java Professional

#### **PROFILE**

Staff Software Engineer with 9+ years of experience in full stack web application development. Self motivated problem solver with a broad exposure to different systems and technologies. Comfortable working in fast paced, dynamic environments with a passion for mentoring and teaching others.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## Staff Software Engineer for UserVoice

2017 - Present

- Full stack engineer using React, Web Components, Go, Ruby on Rails, and MySQL to build performant, high volume web applications
- Architected and implemented SOC2 compliant authentication system for all customer-facing applications
- Organized engineering efforts to establish GDPR compliance throughout products and services
- Established company-wide frontend stack, leveraging TypeScript, React, Apollo GraphQL, and Material UI to improve app load times by > 400%
- Created private NPM registry and packages for sharing resources between codebases
- Devised migration strategies for iteratively moving existing AngularJS applications to new React stack
- Constructed automated spam detection platform by integrating third-party services and pattern detection methods
- Worked with team to create new billing and permissions services
- Mentored and collaborated with teammates to promote coding best practices
- · Presented technical talks to department spanning topics such as React, GraphQL, caching, and metrics/monitoring

## **Software Engineer for WebAssign**

2015 - 2017

- Full stack engineer responsible for building new, user facing, applications using MEAN stack
- Served as Subject Matter Expert for front-end development
- Worked with team in building new frameworks and establishing best practices for modern web applications
- Developed component-based front-end to meet W3C accessibility standards

## **Software Engineer for CapTech Consulting**

2014 - 2015

- Worked with Directors to develop company-wide application for generating organizational charts
- Member of Global Resource Management Team responsible for creating company-wide tools and applications

## Java Software Engineer for Bank of America

- Worked with team of developers in constructing new check image processing system
- Implemented new partitioning strategy for Oracle database
- Designed and build automated system for end-to-end regression testing

## Java / Mobile Web Developer for Capital One

• Worked with team to provide triage for mobile apps and web services

## PROJECTS, RESEARCH, AND PUBLICATIONS

Author for Better Programming

https://medium.com/@amoore1337

Shape My Tasks

https://shapemytasks.com/ https://moorenet.tech/

Projects & Experiments

Android in Robotics and Data Acquisition

Samford University Showcase, 2014